# **Amber Theinert**

1816 Lullaby Lane, Midwest City, OK 73130 atheinert@gmail.com • (405) 219-2623

#### **About Me:**

Highly motivated, skill orientated professional, with a solid history of outreach, website content management, public relations and event management experience. Extremely organized with a proven track record and the ability to plan and manage several events/projects and meet strict deadlines, while exceeding management's goals and objectives.

### **Experience**

#### **Training Communications Associate**

#### Memorial Insitute for the Prevention of Terrorism

Oklahoma City, OK 2007 – present

Manage and direct the post-sales campaign for our training program, including relationship management, promotions and information sharing. Maintain the Institute's web presence, including the website, promoting through e-mail marketing and social media outlets, maintaining web analytics and SEO. Creating visuals and promotional pieces to ensure clear, consistent messaging.

#### **Senior Capitol Reporter**

#### Oklahoma Publishing Today (now dba eCapitol.net)

Oklahoma City, OK 2003 – 2004; 2006 - 2007

Managed capitol reporters and ensuring they met publishing deadlines while carrying out on stories. Assisted in the creation and start up of a new website, as well as managing the opening media event to announce the creation of the website. Organized daily assignments for reporters and managed the state capitol office during legislative sessions.

#### **Director of Student Activities**

#### Navarro College

Corsicana, TX 2004 – 2006

Coordinated all student activities, including advising and directing the Student Government Association and was named TJCSGA Region III Advisor of the Year. Organized and managed the Freshman Orientation program, which included supervising Orientation Leaders and multiple events.

### **Expertise**

Knowledge in program management, creating & maintaining departmental/event budgets, writing/editing, graphic design and parliamentary procedure. Computer knowledge in Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Acrobat Professional, Water CMS, NukeDotNet CMS, SEO, HTML, Wordpress, Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, Google+, Instagram, Vine, Woopra Web Analytics, Google Web Analytics, ACT, Contact Management, Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher and Outlook.

### **Education**

#### **University of Oklahoma**

#### Courses taken in pursuance of M.A. in Strategic Communications, Emphasis in Public Relations

Professional Project Researches Gender in Sports Information Directing, Elective Courses in Higher Education Administration, Graduate Student Senate, Gaylord Scholarship Recipient, Sooner Heritage Scholarship Recipient

#### **Southwestern Oklahoma State University**

#### B.A. in Communication Arts, Minor in Marketing

Student Government Association Officer, Freshmen Orientation Leader, Collegiate Activities Board, Gamma Delta Kappa, Dean's List, OKC Women in Communications Scholarship Recipient

## Community

Oklahoma Developmental Disabilities Council Partners in Policymaking Program (2013 - present), Oklahoma Center for Nonprofits Standards for Excellence Program (2013), Autism Oklahoma PieceWalk & 5k Committee (2012 - present), Red Coyote Racing Team (2011 - present), OK Landrunner (2013 - present)